Preliminary guide to the Warren Mcgee collection 1890-1998
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Warren Mcgee collection>
1890-1998
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-2681 mhslibrary@mt.gov
60:5-7
McGee, Warren, 1914-
22 linear feet of shelf space
Retired railroad conductor and photographer from Livingston. Collection includes subject files [predominantly clippings] (1960s-1990s) on Amtrak, the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, the Burlington Northern merger, the Milwaukee Road abandonment, railroad safety, train wrecks, Railpax, plus a wide variety of political and environmental issues. In addition, there are survey field books (1918, 1920) for the Cooke-Gardner Railway (books give station, elevation, grade, cut or fill, area's excavation and embankment, and remarks; topograph notes; or preliminary levels).
Biographical Note:
Warren Russell McGee was born in Livingston, Montana, on September 7, 1914, the second child of Howard E. and Mildred (Reeves) McGee. He graduated from Park County High School in 1933 during the depths of the Great Depression. As a young man, he took whatever work he could find, including dish washing for a road construction crew on the Beartooth Highway, laboring on the Fort Peck Dam, and construction work on Dunraven Pass in Yellowstone National Park. In 1936 he began his lifetime work for the Northern Pacific Railway, as a brakeman. He was drafted into the Army Air Force in March 1942 and served as a maintenance man in a photo reconnaisance squadron in the Solomon's and Saipan. After his discharge from the military in September 1945, he returned to work for the Northern Pacific Railway. He worked his way up to conductor and continued to work for the Northern Pacific, Burlington Northern, and Amtrak until his retirement on October 31, 1975.
McGee was chairman from 1960 until 1970 of the Livingston Anti-Merger Committee, which was dedicated to opposing the creation of the Burlington Northern Railroad. He was also an outspoken advocate of the continuation of rail service to Montana communities. McGee made two unsuccessful campaigns for public office, first in 1966 when he ran for the Legislature, and again in 1971 when he ran as a delegate to the Montana Constitutional Convention. In spite of his two defeats he remained very active with the Montana Democratic Party.
During his service in World War II, McGee became an expert photographer. He combined that skill with his love of trains into a hobby of railroad photography. He compiled one of the most complete photo documentations of locomotives in existence.
In September 1946, McGee married Bernice Lavold, daughter of Knute and Helen (Berg) Lavold of Big Timber. They had one son, Howard, who died in an automobile accident at the age of 22. Bernice shared Warren's passion for politics and railroads, writing many letters to the editor. She was active in the community as a Cub Scout den mother, as a founder of Livingston's Meals on Wheels Program, as a board member for the Livingston Memorial Hospital, and numerous other community projects. She died February 15, 2001.
Papers. 1890-1998 [bulk 1960-1998]. 19 linear feet. Collection includes subject files [predominantly clippings] (1960s-1990s) on Amtrak, the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, the Burlington Northern merger, the Milwaukee Road abandonment, railroad safety, train wrecks, Railpax, plus a wide variety of political and environmental issues. In addition, there are survey field books (1918, 1920) for the Cooke-Gardner Railway (books give station, elevation, grade, cut or fill, area's excavation and embankment, and remarks; topograph notes; or preliminary levels).
by subgroup and series
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
Published material separated to Library
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Warren McGee
  - Biographical Materials
    - Clippings and writings (including biographical sketch from History of Park County, articles from Bozeman Chronicle, obituary of Bernice McGee, nomination for Montana Senior Citizen of the Year, notes) (Box-folder 1 / 1)
  - General Correspondence
    - A-B, 1970s- 1990s (Box-folder 1 / 2)
    - Norman L. Cunningham (correspondence, reports, etc. re packing industry), 1965-1968 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
    - C-F, 1958-1992 (Box-folder 1 / 4-5)
    - Great Northern Railroad (re his photographs), 1943-1952 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
    - G-K, 1970s- 1990s? (Box-folder 1 / 7-8)
    - Kalmbach Publishing Company (Trains Magazine), 1942-2000 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
    - Bill Kratville, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
    - L, 1957-1995 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
    - Mike Mansfield [see also political and railroad subject files], 1968-1970 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
    - M, 1959-1996 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
    - National Railway Historical Society. Pacific Northwest Chapter, 1977-1992 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
    - Northern Pacific Railway Company (re his photos), 1937-1945 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
    - N, 1955-1998 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
    - Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
    - O-P, 1976-1999 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
    - Don H. Roberts (enclosing lists of negatives, rosters, etc.), 1938-1964 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
    - R-V, 1973-1997 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
    - Horace B. Williams, 1959 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
    - W-Z, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
    - Chronological file, 1929-2001 (Box-folder 1 / 23-34)
  - Subject Files
    - Agriculture, grazing, grain, etc.: clippings, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 2 / 1-2)
    - Airplanes and other transportation: clippings, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
    - Air pollution: clippings, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
    - Alaska (includes A-Test on Amchitka Island; highway): clippings, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 2 / 5)
    - Alaska and Canada (predominantly railroads; also economy, natural resources, etc.): clippings, 1963-1982 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
    - Alaska oil pipeline: clippings, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 2 / 7)
    - American Freedom Train (correspondence, clippings, etc.), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
    - Amtrak: correspondence, 1971-1995 (Box-folder 2 / 9-15)
    - Amtrak: annual reports, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
    - Amtrak: Butte to Salt Lake City (includes memorandum of interrogatories by Montana Passenger Train Users Association; brief; Montana House Joint Resolution) (Box-folder 2 / 17)
    - Amtrak: clippings, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 2 / 18-29)
    - Amtrak: clippings, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
    - Amtrak: Dr. Richard L. Day, University of Idaho (re research on train passengers; letters to politicians), 1971-1980 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
    - Amtrak: employee rail pass, 1975 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
    - Amtrak: employee rules, etc., 1971-1975 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
    - Amtrak: legislation, resolutions, etc., 1974-1985 (Box-folder 3 / 5-6)
    - Amtrak: notices, bulletins, etc., 1973-1975 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
    - Amtrak: publications, brochures, etc., 1970s- 1980s (Box-folder 3 / 8)
    - Amtrak: scheduling bulletins, circulars, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 3 / 9-10)
    - Amtrak: U.S. Dept. of Labor rail worker protection plan, 1971 (Box-folder 3 / 11)
    - Amtrak: usage maps, statistics, etc., 1970-1974 (Box-folder 3 / 12)
    - Amtrak: misc. (Box-folder 3 / 13)
    - Auto junk yards: clippings, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 3 / 14)
    - Bannack and Big Hole history: mimeos (by Homer Faust and Beaverhead Chamber of Commerce) (Box-folder 3 / 15)
    - Big Sky of Montana resort: clippings, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 3 / 16-17)
    - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen: correspondence with Robert C. Theurer (includes court case), 1965-1970 (Box-folder 3 / 18)
    - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen: agreements re railroad merger, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 3 / 19)
    - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen: membership lists, 1967 (Box-folder 3 / 20)
    - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen: seniority lists, 1944-1967 (Box-folder 3 / 21-23)
    - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen: Special Board of Adjustment decision, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 3 / 24)
    - Burlington Northern: correspondence (also includes some Northern Pacific), 1962-1990 (Box-folder 3 / 25)
    - Burlington Northern: abandonment (includes correspondence, bulletins, orders, etc.), 1960-1988 (Box-folder 3 / 26)
    - Burlington Northern: abandonment (includes sale to Washington Corporation: Montana Rail Link) [clippings], 1981-1992 (Box-folder 3 / 27-28)
    - Burlington Northern: agreements with engineers, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 3 / 29)
    - Burlington Northern: bulletins, notices, circulars, directives, etc., 1971-1994 (Box-folder 4 / 1-6)
    - Burlington Northern: coal train specifications, 1971 (Box-folder 4 / 7)
    - Burlington Northern: corporate affairs [clippings], 1981-1989 (Box-folder 4 / 8)
    - Burlington Northern: Rep. Byron L. Dorgan (re proposed land grant forfeiture), 1983-1984 (Box-folder 4 / 9)
    - Burlington Northern: employee lists, 1970 (Box-folder 4 / 10)
    - Burlington Northern: Laurel Terminal on-time performance, 1985 (Box-folder 4 / 11)
    - Burlington Northern: line-ups, messages, locomotive movements, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 4 / 12)
    - Burlington Northern: Livingston Anti-Merger Committee petition to Interstate Commerce Commission and correspondence, 1961 (Box-folder 4 / 13)
    - Burlington Northern: locomotive assignments and stored units, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 4 / 14-16)
    - Burlington Northern: locomotive lists, by number (includes original number, serial number, builder, model, year, power, and design), 1973 (Box-folder 4 / 17)
    - Burlington Northern: locomotive roster, 1979 (Box-folder 4 / 18)
    - Burlington Northern: locomotives and crews dispatched, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4 / 19)
    - Burlington Northern: merger [clippings], 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4 / 20-22)
    - Burlington Northern: merger, proposed [brochure], 1961 (Box-folder 4 / 23)
    - Burlington Northern: merger (includes correspondence, ICC docket, Livingston Anti-Trust Committee appeal), 1962-1969 (Box-folder 4 / 24)
    - Burlington Northern: Monday morning reports from Wayne Hatton, Billings VP, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4 / 25)
    - Burlington Northern: Rocky Mountain Division bulletins, 1970-1972, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 4 / 26-27)
    - Burlington Northern: Rocky Mountain Division notices, 1970-1971, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 5 / 1-2)
    - Burlington Northern: Safety Committee, Mandan, N.D. (includes minutes, and bulletins), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
    - Burlington Northern: speed violations, 1980 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
    - Burlington Northern: timeslip preparation information, 1982 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
    - Burlington Northern: track profiles, Williston to Havre, n.d. (Box-folder 5 / 6)
    - Burlington Northern: train location bulletins, 1981, 1991 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
    - Burlington Northern: Winona Bridge Railway Company subsidiary [clippings], 1987-1988 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
    - Burlington Northern: Yard Office [correspondence and requisitions], 1971-1973 (Box-folder 5 / 9)
    - Burlington Northern: Yellowstone Division bulletins, 1971 (Box-folder 5 / 10)
    - Burlington Northern: Yellowstone Division notices, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 5 / 11)
    - Burlington Northern: clippings, 1971-1991 (Box-folder 5 / 12-15)
    - Burlington Northern Santa Fe: clippings, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 5 / 16)
    - Butte prostitution and corruption: clippings, 1968 (Box-folder 5 / 17)
    - Cabooses: clippings, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 5 / 18)
    - "CBQ-Milw-UP" (re Chicago, Burlington and Quincy; Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul; and Union Pacific railroads) [clippings], 1961-1979 (Box-folder 5 / 19)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: abandonment [correspondence], 1978-1980 (Box-folder 5 / 20)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: abandonment [ICC hearing], 1979? (Box-folder 5 / 21)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: abandonment [clippings], 1977-1985 (Box-folder 5 / 22-25)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: annual report, 1977 (Box-folder 5 / 26)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: bulletins, orders, etc., 1946-1982 (Box-folder 5 / 27)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: history [mostly clippings], 1960-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 5 / 28)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: history (Red Hanley and Dave Emerson articles), 1980, 1988 (Box-folder 6 / 1)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: history (Bill Wilkerson correspondence and articles), 1956-1998 (Box-folder 6 / 2-4)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: dispatcher bulletins, etc., 1933-1960 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: reports, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 6 / 6-7)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: miscellany (Box-folder 6 / 8)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul [Milwaukee Road]: clippings (Box-folder 6 / 9)
    - Chicago Milwaukee Corporation: annual reports, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 6 / 10)
    - Chicago Milwaukee Corporation: quarterly reports [scattered], 1983-1988 (Box-folder 6 / 11)
    - Coal mining; strip mining; Colstrip generating plant: clippings, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 6 / 12)
    - Coins: clippings, 1964-1978 (Box-folder 6 / 13)
    - Colstrip (town and power generating plant): clippings, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 6 / 14)
    - Constitutional amendments, proposed, 1970 (Box-folder 6 / 15)
    - Dams and water resources: clippings, 1964-1982 (Box-folder 6 / 16-20)
    - Dams: Libby (clippings), 1964-1974 (Box-folder 6 / 21)
    - Dams: Missouri River, including Wild and Scenic River designation (clippings), 1964-1976 (Box-folder 6 / 22)
    - Dams: Reichle (clippings), 1965-1975 (Box-folder 7 / 1)
    - Dams: Sun River (clippings), 1965-1968 (Box-folder 7 / 2)
    - Dams: Yellowstone River, including Allenspur (correspondence, miscellany), 1972-1976 (Box-folder 7 / 3)
    - Dams: Yellowstone River, including Allenspur (clippings), 1968-1977 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
    - Dams: Yellowtail (clippings), 1967-1974 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
    - Farmers: prices and problems (clippings), 1964-1973 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
    - Federal Aeronautics Administration (FAA) station: clippings, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 7 / 7)
    - Fish and game; recreation; Yellowstone National Park: clippings, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 7 / 8)
    - Foreign trade: clippings, 1071-1975 (Box-folder 7 / 9)
    - Full crew laws and regulations: summary by Bureau of Railway Economics, 1962 (Box-folder 7 / 10)
    - Full crew laws and regulations: legislation, circulars, etc., 1957-1970 (Box-folder 7 / 11)
    - Full crew laws and regulations: clippings, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
    - Glasgow Air Force Base: clippings, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 7 / 13)
    - Government, economy, liabilities: clippings, 1962-1982 (Box-folder 7 / 14-18)
    - Great Northern Railway: history (articles, brochures, circulars) (Box-folder 7 / 19)
    - Great Northern Railway: history (clippings), 1937-1997 (Box-folder 7 / 20)
    - Great Northern Railway: list of steam locomotives, 1974 (Box-folder 7 / 21)
    - Great Northern Railway: maps, 1890-1902 (Box-folder 7 / 22)
    - Great Northern Railway: memoranda re non-common carrier branch lines (also includes Northern Pacific Railway), 1920 (Box-folder 7 / 23)
    - Great Northern Railway: Photos, photo lists, etc. (Cordell R. Newby), 1961-1964 (Box-folder 7 / 24)
    - Great Northern Railway: reports to annual meeting, 1963, 1965 (Box-folder 7 / 25)
    - Great Northern Railway: track profiles, 1963, 1965 (Box-folder 7 / 26)
    - Great Northern Railway: miscellany (Box-folder 7 / 27)
    - Great Northern Railway: clippings, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 7 / 28)
    - Great Northern Railway Historical Society: calendars, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 8 / 1)
    - Great Northern Railway Historical Society: constitution, bylaws, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 8 / 2)
    - Great Northern Railway Historical Society: conventions, brochures, etc., 1984-1996 (Box-folder 8 / 3)
    - Great Northern Railway Historical Society: membership lists, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 8 / 4)
    - Great Northern Railway, Veterans Association of the: annual meeting program, 1939 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
    - Highways: triple trailer trucks (correspondence, flyers, court case, etc.), 1980, 1990 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
    - Highways: clippings, 1960-1983 (Box-folder 8 / 7-10)
    - Highways: Clark Canyon, Wyo. (clippings), 1970-1978 (Box-folder 8 / 11)
    - Holbrook United Methodist Church, 1983, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 8 / 12)
    - Indians: resources, taxes, attitudes (clippings), 1972-1974 (Box-folder 8 / 13)
    - Iron Horse Museum and Cultural Center, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 8 / 14)
    - Isaac Walton Inn "Essex-press", 1986-1990 (Box-folder 8 / 15)
    - Labor unions (includes Tony Boyle): clippings, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 8 / 16)
    - Livingston businesses, social life, history, etc.: clippings, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 8 / 17)
    - Livingston City Commission: correspondence, etc. (Bernice McGee was elected in 1995), 1995-1998 (Box-folder 8 / 18)
    - Livingston City Commission: clippings (Bernice McGee was elected in 1985 and 1995; also includes some Park County government), 1979-1997 (Box-folder 8 / 19)
    - Livingston City Parks: clippings and correspondence (includes controversies around Warren McGee's volunteer work), 1986-1990 (Box-folder 8 / 20)
    - Livingston Memorial Hospital: correspondence, bylaws, clippings, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 8 / 21)
    - Livingston rail shop clean-up: clippings, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 8 / 22)
    - Warren and Bernice McGee activities, honors, controversies, etc. (clippings), 1961-2001 (Box-folder 8 / 23-25)
    - Medicare, Social Security, retirement: circulars, brochures, etc., 1965?- 1973 (Box-folder 8 / 26)
    - Medicare, Social Security, retirement: clippings, 1965-1979 (Box-folder 8 / 27-28)
    - Milwaukee Road Historical Association: circulars, treasurers' reports, etc., 1986-1994 (Box-folder 8 / 29)
    - Mining: Anaconda Company's Lincoln mine, etc.; air pollution (clippings), 1968-1970 (Box-folder 8 / 30)
    - Mining: clippings, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 8 / 31)
    - Montana Constitutional Convention (re Warren McGee's campaign for delegate): clippings, circulars, financial reports, etc., 1971 (Box-folder 8 / 32)
    - Montana Fish and Game Dept. (also includes general wildlife issues): miscellany, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 8 / 33)
    - Montana Fish and Game Dept. (also includes general wildlife issues): clippings, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 8 / 34-35)
    - Montana Fish and Game Dept. (also includes general wildlife issues): clippings, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 9 / 1-4)
    - Montana Fish and Game Dept.: buffalo (clippings), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 9 / 5)
    - Montana Fish and Game Dept.: predator control, 1080, eagle shootings (clippings), 1971-1978 (Box-folder 9 / 6)
    - Montana Fish and Game Dept.: Pryor wild horse herd (clippings), 1968-1976 (Box-folder 9 / 7)
    - Montana Fish and Game Dept.: Yellowstone National Park elk; Gallatin elk hunt (clippings), 1971-1978 (Box-folder 9 / 8)
    - Montana Legislature: clippings (includes Warren McGee's campaign for legislature, 1966), 1963-1967 (Box-folder 9 / 9-10)
    - Montana Public Service Commission: clippings, 1964-1982 (Box-folder 9 / 11)
    - Montana State Rail Plan: agreement with Burlington Northern, 1984 (Box-folder 9 / 12)
    - Museums (re loans and donations) (Box-folder 9 / 13)
    - National and international politics: correspondence, circulars, etc., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 9 / 14)
    - National and international politics: clippings [unsorted], 1977-1984 (Box-folder 9 / 15)
    - National Association of Railroad Passengers: correspondence, brochures, etc., 1969-1997 (Box-folder 9 / 16-18)
    - National Rifle Association: clippings, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 9 / 19)
    - Natural resources: correspondence with Congressmen, brochures, etc., 1970-1977 (Box-folder 9 / 20)
    - Natural resources: clippings, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 9 / 21)
    - Natural resources: coal, including Colstrip power generating plant, strip mining, Indian coal leases, etc. (clippings), 1970-1974 (Box-folder 9 / 22-25)
    - Natural resources: coal, including Zweifel mining claim scam (clippings), 1971-1983 (Box-folder 10 / 1-3)
    - Natural resources: lumber industry (clippings), 1967-1982 (Box-folder 10 / 4-5)
    - Natural resources: nuclear industry (circulars, etc.), 1973-1979 (Box-folder 10 / 6)
    - Natural resources: nuclear industry (clippings), 1968-1979 (Box-folder 10 / 7)
    - Natural resources: oil and gas industry (clippings), 1967-1979 (Box-folder 10 / 8-9)
    - Natural resources: clippings [unsorted], 1960s- 1980s (Box-folder 10 / 10-13)
    - Nerve gas, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 10 / 14)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 10 / 15)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: annual reports, brief reports, 1961-1965, 1982 (Box-folder 10 / 16)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: articles (Box-folder 10 / 17)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: brochures (Oregon, Washington, Idaho) (Box-folder 10 / 18)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: brochures (Yellowstone National Park), 1917, 1938 (Box-folder 10 / 19)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: brochures (miscellaneous, includes some duplicates and some photocopies) (Box-folder 10 / 20-21)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: circular letters, forms, statistics, etc., 1960s (Box-folder 10 / 22)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: forms, statistics, etc., 1960s (Box-folder 11 / 1)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: history (photocopies of documents), 1890s- 1940s (Box-folder 11 / 2)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: history (articles) (Box-folder 11 / 3)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: history (clippings; unsorted), 1883-1982 (Box-folder 11 / 4-5)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: history (notes) (Box-folder 11 / 6)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: history (Jerry Masters slide show narrative "St. Paul and Northern Pacific Railway brings the NPRR to St. Paul") (Box-folder 11 / 7)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: list of stations, n.d. (Box-folder 11 / 8)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: locomotives (clippings, etc.), 1954-1956 (Box-folder 11 / 9)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: locomotive diagrams and drawings [photocopies of blueprints], 1893-1949 (Box-folder 11 / 10-15)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: memoranda, 1943-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 16)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: merger, loss of service (clippings), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 11 / 17)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: menus, souvenires, etc. (Box-folder 11 / 18)
    - Northern Pacific Railway. Rocky Mountain Division bulletins, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 11 / 19)
    - Northern Pacific Railway. Rocky Mountain Division notices, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 11 / 20)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: statistical information (trackage, cabooses, locomotives, etc.) (Box-folder 11 / 21)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: telegrams, train orders, etc., 1949-1977 (Box-folder 11 / 22)
    - Northern Pacific Railway: vacation days, 1970 (Box-folder 11 / 23)
    - Northern Pacific Railway Historical Association: circular, n.d. (Box-folder 11 / 24)
    - Northern Pacific Railway, Veterans Association of: convention materials, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 11 / 25)
    - Northern Tier Pipeline: clippings, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 11 / 26)
    - Northwest Railroad Historical Society bulletin [separate to library??], 1939-1940 (Box-folder 11 / 27)
    - Eli Oliver, Economic Advisor to Railway Brotherhoods: speech, n.d. (Box-folder 11 / 28)
    - Outdoor recreation: brochures, legislation, regulation, etc., 1966-1971 (Box-folder 11 / 29)
    - Outdoor recreation: clippings, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 11 / 30)
    - Park County Courthouse: clippings, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 11 / 31)